Guide to the Alfred Tennyson Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Alfred Tennyson collection
1775-1929
GEN MSS 276
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
8.2
(16 boxes) + 1 broadside folder
Correspondence, writings, documents, printed material, and photographs by or about Alfred Tennyson and his family. The correspondence is primarily that of Alfred Tennyson, Hallam Tennyson, and Emily Sellwood Tennyson, and correspondents include such prominent writers as Charlotte Brontë, Thomas Carlyle, Henry Wadsworth Longfellow, and John Ruskin. There are miscellaneous autograph manuscript poems by Alfred as well as page and galley proofs. Also present are materials gathered for a life of Alfred Tennyson by Hallam Tennyson, annotations in the London 1906 edition of Hallam Tennyson's Memoir, by Hallam and Mary Emily Prinsep Tennyson, including extracts from printed works, Emily Sellwood Tennyson's diary, and copies of letters to, from and about Alfred Tennyson. Other papers present include photographs, funeral programs, an autograph manuscript schedule by Edward Lear of drawings illustrating Tennyson's poems, and two pen and ink self-portraits by Alfred Tennyson.
Tennyson, Alfred Tennyson, Baron, 1809-1892
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ongoing collection of documents acquired by gift and purchase from various sources. Type of accession (gift or purchase) and date of acquisition is noted in the box-and-folder list. For further information, consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Restricted Fragile in box 15 may only be consulted with permission of the appropriate curator. Preservation photocopies for reference use have been substituted in the main files.
Scope and Contents
This finding aid encompasses accessions of single manuscripts and small groups of manuscripts and other papers, by or pertaining to Alfred Tennyson and his family, which the library has chosen to group and list as an artificial collection. There are two series: the first series, Purchase from Colonel E. S. M. Prinsep, is organized into five subseries: Correspondence, Writings, Printed Material, Photographs, and Other Papers. Correspondence, Writings, and Other Papers are arranged by materials belonging to Alfred Tennyson, Hallam Tennyson, Emily Sellwood Tennyson, Other Tennyson Family, and Other Correspondence. Writings includes annotations to Hallam Tennyson's Memoir of his father, which includes copies of letters to and from Alfred Tennyson and his wife. The second series, Additional Materials, consists of other materials acquired from various sources, and is organized into three subseries: Correspondence, Writings, and Other Papers. These subseries are arranged by materials belonging to Alfred Tennyson, Hallam Tennyson, and Other Tennyson Family. Volumes contains those volumes which did not fit in the previous boxes, but which are not oversize. Oversize contains material from Series I, arranged in box order.
English poetry -- 19th century; Poets, English -- 19th century -- Portraits; Poets, English -- 19th century; Photographic prints; Brontë, Charlotte, 1816-1855; Carlyle, Thomas, 1795-1881; Longfellow, Henry Wadsworth, 1807-1882; Ruskin, John, 1819-1900; Tennyson, Alfred Tennyson, Baron, 1809-1892 -- Archives; Tennyson, Alfred Tennyson, Baron, 1809-1892; Tennyson, Emily Sellwood Tennyson, Baroness, 1813-1896; Tennyson, Hallam Tennyson, Baron, 1852-1928 ( Alfred lord Tennyson, a memoir); Tennyson, Hallam Tennyson, Baron, 1852-1928; Tennyson, Lionel, 1854-1886; Tennyson, Mary Emily Prinsep Hichens; Tennyson family
- Purchase from Colonel E. S. M. Prinsep, 1775-1929; Series I; 3.6; (9 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Series I, Purchase from Colonel E. S. M. Prinsep, is organized into five subseries: Correspondence, Writings, Printed Material, Photographs, and Other Papers. Correspondence, Writings, and Other Papers are arranged by materials belonging to: Alfred Tennyson, Hallam Tennyson, Emily Sellwood Tennyson, Other Tennyson Family, and Other Correspondence.
  - CORRESPONDENCE
    - Tennyson, Alfred
      - Incoming
        - About, Edmond François Valentin. AL [in an unidentified hand], signed by Edmond About, President of the Société des Gens des Lettres, Paris, 1878 Apr 13 (Box 1, Folder 1)
        - Atkinson, H. H. ALS, Trenton, Missouri, 1873 Oct 30 (Box 1, Folder 2)
        - Bateman, Sidney Frances Cowell. 2 ALS, [London], [1875-76] (Box 1, Folder 3)
        - Bowen, L. ALS, Freshwater, I[sle of] W[ight], 1873 May 4 (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - Brontë, Charlotte. ALS, signed "Currer Bell," Haworth, 1847 Jun 16 (Box 1, Folder 5)
        - Brookfield, William Henry. ALS, Sheffield, 1832 Aug 15 (Box 1, Folder 6)
          Mentions James Montgomery
        - Browning, Elizabeth Barrett. ANS, London, 1852 Aug 12 (Box 1, Folder 7)
          Accompanied by a postscript by Robert Browning and a second envelope postmarked Aug 12 1852
        - Browning, Robert. ALS with envelope, London, 1876 Dec 21 (Box 1, Folder 8)
        - Carew, Mrs. James
          Related Archival Materials note
          See: Terry, Ellen, Box 1, folder 67
        - Carlyle, Thomas. 3 ALS, Chelsea, 1850-69, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 9)
        - Carnevali, Luigi. 2 ALS, Mantua, 1882 (Box 1, Folder 10)
        - Cator, Julia Maria Frances Hallam
          See: Lennard, Julia Maria Frances Hallam, Box 1, folder 33
        - Cerny, Paul. ALS, Prague, 1881 Jun 12 (Box 1, Folder 11)
        - Dickens, Charles. 2 ALS, 1843, 1852 (Box 1, Folder 12)
        - Dodgson, Charles Lutwidge. 3 ALS, 1870 Mar (Box 1, Folder 13)
        - Emma, Queen Consort of Kaméhaméhe IV, King of Hawaii. ALS, London, 1865 Nov 30 (Box 1, Folder 14)
        - Field, Walter. ALS, [London], 1891 Feb 10
          See: Box 9, folder 403
        - FitzGerald, Edward. 2 ALS., 1835-76 (Box 1, Folder 15)
          1835 Jul 2 letter is scorched and partly illegible
        - Forster, John. AL and 3 ALS, 1846-57 (Box 1, Folder 16)
        - Franklin, Jane Griffin. 2 ALS, [1872-73] (Box 1, Folder 17)
          1873 Mar 22 letter is addressed also to Emily Sellwood Tennyson; it is preceded by a note to Emily Sellwood Tennyson written in an unidentified hand
        - Gladstone, William Ewart. ALS, Hawarden Castle, Chester, 1875 Jan 5 (Box 1, Folder 18)
        - Gosse, Sir Edmund William. ALS (fragment), [London], 1889 May 10 (Box 1, Folder 19)
        - Gower, Ronald Charles Sutherland. ALS, [London], 1871 Mar 27 (Box 1, Folder 20)
        - Grant, Sir Alexander, bart. ALS (fragment) (Box 1, Folder 21)
        - Hallam, Henry. 10 ALS, 1845-53 (Box 1, Folder 22)
          Letter of 1850 May accompanied by a copy, in an unidentified hand
        - Hallam, Julia Maria Frances
        - Hewlett, Henry Gay. ALS, [London], 1869 Aug 5 (Box 1, Folder 23)
        - Holder, C. J. ALS, Lee, 1883 Oct 17 (Box 1, Folder 24)
        - Houghton, Richard Mockton Milnes, 1st baron. 3 ALS., [1834?-36] (Box 1, Folder 25)
          [1834?] letter mutilated
        - Hugo, Victor. ALS, Paris, 1877 Jun 14 (Box 1, Folder 26)
        - Hunt, Leigh. ALS, [London], [1837] Jul 21 (Box 1, Folder 27)
        - Ishister, William. ALS, London, 1870 Feb 28 (Box 1, Folder 28)
        - Jesse, Emily Tennyson. 4 ALS, [185?-75?] (Box 1, Folder 29)
        - Kemble, Frances Anne. 2 ALS, ca. 1855, [1880] (Box 1, Folder 30)
        - Kemp, W. F. ALS, London, 1855 Oct 11 (Box 1, Folder 31)
        - Kinglake, Alexander William. 2 ALS, [London], 1880, 1889 (Box 1, Folder 32)
        - Lennard, Julia Maria Frances Hallam. 2 ALS, Pickhurst, Bromley, [1859, 1860] (Box 1, Folder 33)
        - Lewis, Robert W. ALS, Germany, 1881 Jan 14 (Box 1, Folder 34)
        - Locker-Lampson, Frederick. 2 ALS, [London], 1869 (Box 1, Folder 35)
          1869 Jul 29 letter concerns Matthew Arnold, and was removed from: Catalogue of pictures...at Farringford (box 9, folder 403)
        - Longfellow, Henry Wadsworth. 4 ALS, 1868-77 (Box 1, Folder 36)
          1877 Nov 27 letter accompanied by an newspaper clipping containing Longfellow's "Wapentake"
        - Lord, Thomas. AL [copy in an unidentified hand of letter dated 1840? Jan 23], Nottingham, [1865] (Box 1, Folder 37)
          [To Alfred Tennyson?] Concerns Lady Godiva
        - Macready, William Charles. ALS, Sherborne Dorset, 1851 Apr 1 (Box 1, Folder 38)
        - Mann, Robert James. ALS, Ventnor, 1855 Mar 13 (Box 1, Folder 39)
          Concerns Alfred Tennyson's "Maud" and Mann's "Maud Vindicated"
        - Mantua and Montferrat, Prince of. 2 letters, written in an unidentified hand, one signed by the Prince of Mantua and Montferrat and the other signed by the Prince's secretary and curator, W. H. Taylor, London, 1882 Apr (Box 1, Folder 40)
        - Marble, Earl. ALS, Boston, 1880 Oct 8 (Box 1, Folder 41)
          Concerns Alfred Tennyson's "Maud"
        - Maurice, Frederick Denison. 2 ALS, 1852 (Box 1, Folder 42)
        - Meiklejohn, John Miller Dow. ALS, University of St. Andrews, 1879 Jan 5 (Box 1, Folder 43)
          Concerns Alfred Tennyson's "The Revenge"
        - Milnes, Richard Monckton
          See: Houghton, Richard Monckton Milnes
        - Monteagle, Thomas Spring-Rice. ALS, Ireland, 1859 Oct 24 (Box 1, Folder 44)
          Removed from: Catalogue of pictures...at Farringford (box 9, folder 403)
        - Mount Carmel Public Schools. ALS, Mt. Carmel, Illinois, 1882 Nov 2 (Box 1, Folder 45)
          With a holograph poem, "Farewell" in Hallam Tennyson's hand on the verso
        - Newman, John Henry. ALS, The Oratory, 1877 Apr 17 (Box 1, Folder 46)
        - Nigra, Costantino. ALS in Italian, London, 1883 Mar 3 (Box 1, Folder 47)
        - Nixon, P. C. ANS, Oporto Ark., 1883 (Box 1, Folder 48)
        - Payne, James Bertrand. ALS, [London], 1868 Apr 17 (Box 1, Folder 49)
          Autograph note on p. 2, signed E[mily] T[ennyson]
        - Peel, Sir Robert. ALS, [London], 1845 Oct 1 (Box 1, Folder 50)
        - Phipps, Sir Charles Beaumont. ALS, Windsor Castle (Box 1, Folder 51)
          Offering Tennyson the Poet Laureateship in the name of Queen Victoria
        - Rawnsley, Robert Drummond Burnell. ALS (fragment) (Box 1, Folder 52)
        - Richardson, David. ALS, Newcastle-on-Tyne, 1878 Jul 12 (Box 1, Folder 53)
        - Rogers, Samuel. 2 ANS, 1842 (Box 1, Folder 54)
        - Rossetti, Dante Gabriel. ALS, [London], 1866 Oct 6 (Box 1, Folder 55)
          Concerns Algernon Charles Swinburne
        - Rough, David. ALS, Nelson, New Zealand, 1860 Dec 10
        - Ruskin, John. 5 ALS, 1855-59 (Box 1, Folder 56)
        - Sandford, Francis Richard John. ALS, [London], 1863 Mar 16
        - Signor
          See: Watts, George Frederick, Box 1, folder 72
        - Spring-Rice, Thomas
          See: Monteagle, Thomas Spring-Rice, Box 1, folder 44
        - Stanley, Arthur Penrhyn. ALS, London, 1875 Jul 26 (Box 1, Folder 57)
        - Steiner, R. Autograph postcard, signed, Innsbruck, [1889?] (Box 1, Folder 58)
        - Sullivan, Sir Arthur Seymour. ALS, [London], 1891 Nov 27 (Box 1, Folder 59)
        - Tauchnitz. ALS (fragment), n.d. (Box 1, Folder 60)
          Not Tauchnitz, Bernhard, Freiherr von
        - Taylor, Sir Henry. 2 ALS, 1852-55 (Box 1, Folder 61)
        - Tennant, Robert J. 3 ALS, [1833]-37 (Box 1, Folder 62)
        - Tennyson, Elizabeth Fytche. ALS, [Hampstead], 1860 Jan 10 (Box 1, Folder 63)
        - Tennyson, Emily Sellwood. 2 AL (fragments), 1876, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 64)
        - Tennyson, Frederick. 2 ALS, 1854
          Also addressed to Emily Sellwood Tennyson
          Related Materials
          See: Box 4, folder 243
        - Tennyson, Frederick. ALS, St. Ewolds, 1884 Jan 23 (Box 1, Folder 65)
        - Tennyson, Hallam. 30 letters to his mother, Emily Sellwood Tennyson, 1869-92
          Letter of 1869 [Apr 4] addressed also to Alfred Tennyson and to Lionel Tennyson. Letter of 1892 Sep 13 addressed also to Alfred Tennyson
          See: Box 3, folders 221-223
        - Tennyson, Lionel. ALS, addressed also to Emily Sellwood Tennyson and Hallam Tennyson, [London], 1876 Apr 29 (Box 1, Folder 66)
          Concerns Alfred Tennyson's "Queen Mary" and Kate Crowe
        - Terry, Ellen. ALS, [London], 1890 Dec 31 (Box 1, Folder 67)
        - Thackeray, William Makepeace. ALS, Folkestone and London, [1859?] Sep (Box 1, Folder 68)
        - Thompson, William Hepworth. ALS, Trinity Lodge, 1868 May 23
        - Tupper, Martin Farquhar. ALS, Eastburne, Sussex, 1871 Jun 9 (Box 1, Folder 69)
        - Waite, John. ALS, Manby Rectory, England, 1866 May 8 (Box 1, Folder 70)
        - Ward, Samuel. ALS, Langham Hotel, 1870 Oct 22
        - Watkinson, Henry. ALS, Spalding, 1888 Jul 14 (Box 1, Folder 71)
        - Watts, George Frederick. ALS, signed "Signor," London, 1862 Apr 2 (Box 1, Folder 72)
        - Weld, Charles Richard. ALS, Somerset House, 1856 Nov 10 (Box 1, Folder 73)
        - Wigan, Alfred Sydney. ALS, Brighton, England, 1861 Jun 15 (Box 1, Folder 74)
        - Unidentified. ALS, Cairnborrow Lodge, Glass, Aberdeenshire, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 75)
        - Unidentified. 2 ALS fragments, Edinburgh and [London], 1869, 1873 (Box 1, Folder 76)
        - Empty envelopes, 1869-72 (Box 1, Folder 77)
      - Outgoing
        - AL to Sir Edwin [Arnold]. Incomplete draft, [Farringford], [1891? Aug] (Box 2, Folder 78)
        - AL [copy in an unidentified hand] to Mrs. [Sidney Frances] Bateman, Farringford, 1875 Dec 14 (Box 2, Folder 79)
        - ALS to [Peter Bayne], Farringford, 1890 Apr 29 (Box 2, Folder 80)
        - AL to "Dulcinea" [i.e. Miss Bousfield] signed "Don Quixote," [Somersby], [1824?] (Box 2, Folder 81)
        - ALS to W[illiam] B[rookfield?], [Chapel House], [1851? Jul] (Box 2, Folder 82)
        - AL (copy in Hallam Tennyson's hand) to William and Jane Brookfield, [Chapel House], [1851] (Box 2, Folder 83)
        - Copy of note addressed to Mrs. [Edward Byles] Cowell, dated 1854 Mar 17, written many years later in a hand imitating Tennyson's (Box 2, Folder 84)
        - ALS (duplicate) to Edward Henry Stanley, Earl of Derby, Farringford, 1876 Apr 10 (Box 2, Folder 85)
        - 5 letters to Aubrey Thomas de Vere, [1842-50?] (Box 2, Folder 86)
        - ALS to [Edward?] Dowden, Farringford, 1887 Oct 29 (Box 2, Folder 87)
        - ALS to Sir Joseph [Fayrer], Farringford, [1879 or 1880?] (Box 2, Folder 88)
        - AL to Edward FitzGerald, [London], [1847 Apr 21] (Box 2, Folder 89)
          The first page is in Tennyson's hand; the remainder of the letter is copied in an unidentified hand, with a note in the same hand appended.
          For second page, see: Box 10, folder 407a
        - ALS and AL to John Forster, [1852, 1855] (Box 2, Folder 90)
          1855 Aug 6 letter is a copy in the hand of Hallam Tennyson
        - AL to [Frederick James] Furnivall. Aldworth, Haslemere, Surrey, [1880] (Box 2, Folder 91)
        - ALS to [Marianne Fytche], [Somersby], [1821?] (Box 2, Folder 92)
        - AL in Emily Sellwood Tennyson's hand, to W. R. Gibbin, Farringford, 1864 Mar 5 (Box 2, Folder 93)
          Accompanied by a photograph of Tennyson
        - ALS to William Ewart Gladstone, Aldworth, Blackdown, Haslemere, 1875 Jan 4 (Box 2, Folder 94)
        - ALS to Richard Monkton Milnes Houghton, 1st baron [Twickenham?], [1852] (Box 2, Folder 95)
        - ALS to Irvine [i.e. Henry Irving], [Farringford], [1875 Oct 28] (Box 2, Folder 96)
        - Draft, in Hallam Tennyson's hand of a letter to [James Russell] Lowell. Surrey, 1880 Sep 18 (Box 2, Folder 97)
        - ALS to [Robert James Mann], Farringford, [1855?] (Box 2, Folder 98)
          Date and name of recipient pencilled on letter in Mary Emily Prinsep Hichens Tennyson's hand
        - AL to [Francisque Xavier Michel]. Incomplete draft, [Farringford], [186-?] (Box 2, Folder 99)
        - Milnes, Richard Monckton
          See: Houghton, Richard Monckton Milnes, Box 1, folder 25
        - ALS to Cardinal [John Henry] Newman, Aldworth, [1882?] (Box 2, Folder 100)
          Date pencilled on letter in an unidentified hand
        - ALS to Coventry Patmore, Bonchurch, Isle of Wight, [1850] Feb 28 (Box 2, Folder 101)
        - ALS and AL to [Charles Kegan] Paul, Farringford, [1874?-75] (Box 2, Folder 102)
          1875 letter is an incomplete draft
        - AL [copy, in Emily Sellwood Tennyson's hand] to Catherine A. Rawnsley, Farringford, 1855 May 2 (Box 2, Folder 103)
          Endorsed by Mary Emily Prinsep Hichens Tennyson
        - ALS to Henry Sellwood, Somersby, [183-?] Jun 7 (Box 2, Folder 104)
        - 3 ALS to James Spedding, [1835?-43] (Box 2, Folder 105)
          1843 Jan 25 Letter illustrated with pen and ink sketch
        - ALS to Charles Villiers Stanford, Farringford, [1875 or 1876] (Box 2, Folder 106)
        - ALS [draft] to Algernon Charles Swinburne, [1891?] Aug
          See: Volumes, box 11, folder 450
        - AL to [W. H. Taylor, private secretary to the Prince of Mantua and Monferrat], incomplete draft, Farringford, [1882] (Box 2, Folder 107)
        - AL to Robert [J. Tennant], [Tunbridge Wells], [1840?] (Box 2, Folder 108)
        - 6 AL and 6 ALS to Emily Sellwood Tennyson, [ca. 1850-77] (Box 2, Folder 109)
        - 2 ALS to Hallam Tennyson, 1860-[75] (Box 2, Folder 110)
          1875 Nov 19 letter is also addressed to Lionel Tennyson
        - Typed copy of a letter to Ticknor & Fields, Farringford, 1858 Dec 11 (Box 2, Folder 111)
          Includes a note, in an unidentified hand, concerning the letter
        - AL [copy in Mary Emily Prinsep Hichens Tennyson's hand?] to [Queen Victoria], [Farringford?], [1861 Dec] (Box 2, Folder 112)
        - AL [copy in an unidentified hand] to W[alt] W[hitman], Farringford, 1891 May 14 (Box 2, Folder 113)
          Accompanied by a manuscript copy in the same hand from Hallam Tennyson to [Horace L. Transel?] 1892 Feb 17
        - ALS to [Edward Whymper], Aldworth, [1892] (Box 2, Folder 114)
          On back of letter in Hallam Tennyson's hand, are copied two stanzas from Sternhold's version of the 18th Psalm
        - Letter (facsimile) to [John Wilson], Somersby, [1834 Apr 26] (Box 2, Folder 115)
          Accompanied by a manuscript copy of the facsimile in an unidentified hand
        - AL [copy, in Mary Emily Prinsep Hichens Tennyson's hand] to an unidentified recipient, Sussex, [1852] (Box 2, Folder 116)
        - ALS to an unidentified recipient, [Farringford], [1853?] (Box 2, Folder 117)
        - AL to an unidentified recipient, Farringford, [1856?] (Box 2, Folder 118)
          Latter part of letter missing
        - ALS to an unidentified recipient [a sculptor], Aldworth, [1873?] (Box 2, Folder 119)
        - 3 ALS to unidentified recipients, 1874-[86] (Box 2, Folder 120)
        - AL to an unidentified recipient, Aldworth, 1885 (Box 2, Folder 121)
          Concerning his acquaintance with Dante Gabriel Rossetti
        - Empty envelopes, 1851, 1869 (Box 2, Folder 122)
    - Tennyson, Hallam
      - Incoming
        - Ainger, Alfred. 3 ALS, various places, 1893, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 123)
        - Anson, Sir William Reynell. ALS, All Souls College, Oxford, 1899 Feb 27 (Box 2, Folder 124)
        - B, M. ALS, n.y. May 8 (Box 2, Folder 125)
          Concerning Frederick Tennyson
        - Bailey, John. ALS, [London], 1927 Jun 9 (Box 2, Folder 126)
          Accompanied by newspaper clipping of a letter written by Bailey to "The Times"
        - Bradley, George Granville. ALS, Demery [Westminster], 1894 Jul 11 (Box 2, Folder 127)
        - Browning, Robert Wiedemann Barrett. Telegram (copy), Knightsbridge, 1889 Dec 13 (Box 2, Folder 128)
          Announces the death of his father, Robert Browning, with part of reply
        - Buchton, Alys M. 2 ALS, Haslemere and Chalice Well, Glastonbury, 1925 Jul (Box 2, Folder 129)
          Accompanied by a program of "The Visit of the Poetry Society to Aldworth...July 11, 1925" and two newspaper clippings. Removed from: Catalogue of pictures...at Farringford (box 9, folder 403)
        - Burne-Jones, Sir Edward Coley. 2 ALS, London and no place, 1896-97 (Box 2, Folder 130)
        - Butler, Henry Montagu. 3 ALS, Trinity Lodge, Cambridge, 1894-1913 (Box 2, Folder 131)
          On verso of second leaf of letter from 1894 Jun 10 in Hallam Tennyson's hand is the inscription placed on the tablet to Alfred Tennyson's memory in Freshwater church
        - Campbell, Mrs. James Dykes. ALS, London, 1910 Apr 29
        - Carpenter, Wiliam Boyd, bp. of Ripon. ALS, London, 1911 Jun 13 (Box 2, Folder 132)
        - Cowley, Arthur Ernest. TLS, Bodleian Library, Oxford, 1922 Jun 21
          Concerns Alfred Tennyson, Gareth and Lynette
        - Cracroft, Sophia. ALS, [London], 1875 Oct 29 (Box 2, Folder 133)
        - Craik, George Lillie. ALS, London, 1889 Jan 21 (Box 2, Folder 134)
          Concerning Goupil and Company's project to publish several of Tennyson's poems with twenty-five illustrations by Edward Lear
        - Daly, Augustin. ALS, Lyceum Theater, 1891 Sep 19 (Box 2, Folder 135)
        - Darwin, Sir George Howard. ALS, [London], 1905 Jul 8 (Box 2, Folder 136)
        - Deakin, Alfred. 2 ALS, Australia, 1908-09 (Box 2, Folder 137)
        - De Vere, Aubrey Thomas. 2 ALS, Curragh Chase, Adare, 1893-94 (Box 2, Folder 138)
        - Dewar, George Albemarle Bertie. ALS, [London], 1907 Feb 12 (Box 2, Folder 139)
        - Eddison, J. E. ALS, The Lodge, Adel, Leeds, 1903 Aug 30 (Box 2, Folder 140)
        - Estes, Dana. 2 ALS, Genoa and Boston, 1887, 1892 (Box 2, Folder 141)
          Concerning the reproduction of Edward Lear's drawings in an edition of Alfred Tennyson's poems. 1887 letter copied in the hand of Mary Tennyson. On first page of 1892 letter is an AMS from Hallam Tennyson to George Lillie Craik referring to this letter
        - FitzGerald, Henrietta Mary Chester. ALS, Henry VIII Gateway, Windsor Castle, n.y. Sep 24 (Box 2, Folder 142)
        - Fletcher, Sir Frank. ANS, Charterhouse, Godalming, 1821 Jul 2
          Concerns Alfred Tennyson, "To the Queen"
        - Froude, James Anthony. ALS, Oxford, [Between 1892 & 1894] (Box 2, Folder 143)
        - Fry, Thomas Charles. ALS, Lincoln, [1926] Mar 10 (Box 2, Folder 144)
          Accompanied by copy in Mary Emily Prinsep Hichens Tennyson's hand. Removed from: Catalogue of pictures...at Farringford (box 9, folder 403)
        - Gladstone, William Ewart. ALS, [London], 1892 Oct 27 (Box 2, Folder 145)
        - Glover, F. ALS, Leeds, 1897 Oct 22 (Box 2, Folder 146)
          Accompanied by two pages of corrections relating to Hallam Tennyson's Memoir, London, 1897
        - Hampden-Cook, Ernest. TLS, Manchester, 1927 Feb 2 (Box 2, Folder 147)
          Includes a quotation from a letter of William Allingham to Henry Septimus Sutton, dated 1852, Aug
        - Harrison, Frederic. ALS, [London], 1897 Dec 12 (Box 2, Folder 148)
        - Havelock, Sir Arthur Elibank. ALS, Government House, Hobart, Tasmania, 1901 Dec 14 (Box 2, Folder 149)
        - Hobart, Anna E. ALS, New York, 1900 Jan 20 (Box 2, Folder 150)
        - Hunt, William Holman. ALS, [London], n.y. May 26 (Box 2, Folder 151)
        - Japikse, Cornelia Geertrui Hendrika. 3 ALS, various places, 1924-26 (Box 2, Folder 152)
          Two letters also addressed to Mary Emily Prinsep Hichens Tennyson. Accompanied by: copies, in Mary Emily Prinsep Hichens Tennyson's hand, of two letters to Hallam Tennyson (one from Prof. A. P. H. Swaen of the University of Amsterdam, dated Jul 5, 1926, and one from George A. Macmillan, dated Jul 8, 1926); a copy in Miss Japikse's hand of the Daily Telegraph 's review of her book The dramas of Alfred Lord Tennyson, Aug 12 1926
        - Jenner, Charles. ALS, Portobello, Midlothian, 1893 Sep 24 (Box 2, Folder 153)
        - Jordan, Leonard. ANS, Isle of Wight, 1926 Nov 13 (Box 2, Folder 154)
          Accompanied by a newspaper clipping relating to Tennyson's poem, "The Revenge"